# **Akash Chaudhary**

**akashchaudhary-portfolio.github.io** | portfolio

achaud10@ucsc.edu | email

**(+1)** 510 203 8170 | mobile

I am a UX researcher who likes exploring the role of human values and motivations behind habit formation around the use of existing and novel technologies. My projects center around exploring the design space for enabling and affording better emotional expressions in the day to day lives of humans. I am currently exploring the experiences of people living in rural areas.

# **EDUCATION**

University of California

Master of Science, Computational Media

Advisor: Dr. Norman Su

CGPA: 3.81

Indian Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology, Production and Industrial

Engineering

Advisor: Dr. Apurbba Kumar Sharma

Major CGPA: 9

**PROJECTS** 

"Are You Still Watching?": Exploring Unintended User Behaviors and Dark Patterns on Video Streaming Platforms

Chaudhary, A., Saroha, J., Monteiro, K.

Advisor: Dr. Angus Forbes, Dr. Aman Parnami

Verbose: Designing a Context-based Educational System for Improving Communicative Expressions

Chaudhary, A., Belani, M., Maheshwari, N.

Advisor : Dr. Aman Parnami

Santa Cruz, USA

Sep 2021 - present

Roorkee, India

Aug 2011 - May 2015

ACM Designing Interactive Systems '22

ACM Mobile HCI '21

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Assistant (Musical Data and Algorithmic Muisc)| University of California, Santa Cruz Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

- I was responsible in assisting my primary instructor in managing the evaluation of course assignments and development of course feedback towards the end.
- O I was also responsible for holding office hours with students to review their work material, answer general course related questions, and provide hands-on assistance on python notebooks in weekly assignments.

 I maintained expertise in subject area throughout in order to expose students with up to date trends and recommend useful resources whenever necessary.

# **UX** Researcher | Authentic User Experience Lab

Apr 2022 - Present

- O I am currently working in collaboration with Dr. Norman Su who is also my lab advisor, to explore and find out the lived experiences of people living in rural areas. We are trying to understand faced by people in rural areas due to gaps in infrastructure facilities, especially computing and transportation.
- We are currently interviewing people to try and understand the problems faced by people in rural areas due to gaps in infrastructure facilities, especially computing and transportation.

# **UX** Researcher | Creative Coding Lab

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

- I collaborated with 4 team members including two mentors UX design expert Dr. Aman Parnami and visualization
  expert, Dr. Angus Forbes, to identify and prioritize a research project involving design critique of video streaming platforms.
- I worked as the first author on a psychology-based user experience study that involved finding deceptive dark design patterns on popular video streaming platforms YouTube, Netflix, PrimeVideo and Disney+ Hotstar.
- Our paper got accepted as a full paper conference submission at ACM Designing Interactive Systems 2022.

### UX/UI Research Associate | Weave Lab

Jan 2018 - July 2021

- I collaborated with lab advisor Dr. Aman Parnami, and 2 other lab members at the Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi, to come up with a novel design for the development of a speech improvement
- Overall, I was responsible for formulating the sketch-based prototypes, conducting user studies, coming up with an
  exhaustive list of options for the visual representation study and getting directly involved with an intern in the development
  of the mobile application.
- I was further involved in analyzing user data, as well as formulating SUS usability scores, SEQ user experience questionnaires and semi-structured interviews.
- O I worked as the first author on our project and our study got accepted as a full paper at ACM Mobile HCI 2021.

#### Research Intern | Verisk

May 2019 - Sep 2019

- O I was responsible for performing data analysis on the Q/A model of the language analysis model BERT for Natural Language Processing tasks on newspaper articles.
- I helped in coming with domain-specific datasets that helped in fine-tuning the BERT model, thereby improving its accuracy by 1.2%.

### Product Manager | Derbii

Nov 2015 - Dec 2017

- I was responsible for documenting user feedback on our early stage android and iOS mobile applications and coming up
  with key areas that need improvement.
- I was also responsible for overseeing other verticals of the startup, namely, Investor Relations and Marketing Growth, as well as being involved in discussions with the tech team for future direction.
- O As a first employee of the company, I was responsible for fostering industry collaborations and managing investor relations.

### **SKILLS**

- O Development Python, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, p5.
- Literature review project management, conducting interviews, surveys, formulating study protocols and procedures, designing prototypes, inter-disciplinary collaboration among cross functional teams, data analysis, writing summary reports and iterative designing.